rootupdate.com 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy - Root Update

### Privacy Policy

 **At rootupdate.com, our main concern is your privacy**. We guarantee that any personal information like your name, address, telephone number and e-mail address provided to us will never be released, sold, or rented to any entities or individuals.

### Personal Details:

rootupdate.com does not need any details or information that can be traced back to or identify a unique user.

### Credit Card Information:

At rootupdate.com, we’ll never ask you for Credit Card details and request you to do not enter your credit card details on any form of This Site.

### External Sites:

rootupdate.com will not be held liable for the content of external sites. You are advised to read the privacy policy of external sites before disclosing any personal information.

### Log Files

Like many other Web sites, rootupdate.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. All of the recorded data like IP addresses and other information are not linked to any information that could personally identify a unique person.

rootupdate.com itself does not use any cookies to store information. Third party service providers however may store information on your computer. Refer to the following sections to understand what information is collected and how to opt out of the process.

### Cookies & 3rd Party Advertisements

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp.

Some of our advertising partners, like Google AdSense, may use cookies and web beacons on our site.

### To EU Users:

Please read our disclosure notice as part of our compliance to the EU user consent policy:

We use cookies to personalise content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyse our traffic. We also share information about your use of our site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners. For more information on how Google uses data when you use our partner’ sites or apps, visit this link:http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/

### Google AdSense

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on rootupdate.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

rootupdate.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. rootupdate.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

At rootupdate.com, we do our best to protect your personal details but we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to This site. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any passwords or other account information. Additionally, other internet sites that may be accessible through rootupdate.com, have separate privacy practices and data, therefore we disclaim any responsibility for their policies or actions.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf  
According to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:  
Users can visit our site anonymously.  
Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website.  
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on the page specified above.  
You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes:  
On our Privacy Policy Page

Can change your personal information:  
By logging in to your account  
How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?  
We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.  
Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?  
It’s also important to note that we do not allow third-party behavioral tracking

### COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We market to

We do not collect information from children under 13  
children under 13.

No  
In order to remove your child’s information please contact the following personnel:  
We adhere to the following COPPA tenants:  
• Parents can review, delete, manage or refuse with whom their child’s information is shared through contacting us directly.  
or contacting us directly.

### Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:  
We will notify you via email  
• Within 7 business days  
We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

### CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, es

that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

### We collect your email address in order to:

• Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions  
To be in accordance with CANSPAM, we agree to the following:  
• Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.  
• Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.  
• Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.  
• Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.  
• Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.  
• Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at  
• Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email.  
and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us From the Contact Us tab or simply mail to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) [dot] com
